--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:春树  字幕来源:射手网  调校:小五  招募Q号:76846146
中世纪的时候 兴起了一种比赛
不管贵族或平民 都为之狂热
即使只有贵族骑士 可以参赛
那就是马上枪术比赛
对某个骑士而言 一个过气的前任冠军
这代表了结束
但对他的平民随从 威廉来说
这只是开始
Should we help him?
我们该帮他吗？
He's due in the lists in two minutes. Two minutes or forfeit.
他得在两分钟内上场 不然就等于弃权
Lend us those.
这借我们
Right. Left.
右边 左边
- Dead.  - Eh?
- 死了  - 什么？
Three scores to none after two lances.
两回合下来的比数是三比零
As long as Sir Ector doesn't fall off his horse,we've won.
只要艾克特爵爷不摔马 我们就赢了
He's dead.
他死了
What do you mean?  - His life's spark is covered in shite.
- 什么意思？  - 他死了
His spirit is gone but his stench remains.
他的精神已远走 但臭味还在
- Does that answer your question?  - No,no,no.
- 这样回答你的问题了吗？  - 不
No,he sleeps. Rouse him.
不 他只是睡着了 叫醒他
I haven't eaten in three days!
我三天没吃东西了！
None of us have!
我们也没吃啊！
- Let's fetch a priest.  - No,he's not dead!
- 我们得去找个神父来  - 不 他没死！
You waKe up! Come on!
醒醒！ 快点！
Come on!
快啊！
You manKy git!
你这臭笨蛋！
Roland.
洛伦
Squire,Sir Ector must report at once or forfeit the match.
随从 艾克特爵爷必须马上报到 不然就等于弃权
He's on his way.
他马上过去
I haven't eaten in three days!
我三天没吃东西了！
Three days! What did you eat,mate?!
三天哪！ 你吃了什么 同伴？
If you wasn't dead,I would Kill you!
如果你没死 我就杀了你！
I'll ride in his place.
我替他上场
Strip his armor. I'm riding in his place.
脱掉他的盔甲 我替他上场
Wat,stop KicKing him! I'm riding in his place. Help me.
华特 别踢他了！ 我替他上场 来帮我
What's your name,William?
威廉 你有什么头衔？
William Thatcher,answer me with your name.
威廉柴契尔 把头衔告诉我啊
It's not Sir William.
不是威廉爵士
It's not Count or DuKe or King William.
也不是伯爵、公爵或威廉国王
I Know that.
这我知道
You must be of noble birth to compete.
要有贵族血统才能参赛
A detail. The landscape is food. Do you want to eat or not?
那不重要 重要的是有饭吃 你到底想不想吃饭？
If the nobles find out,there'll be the devil to pay.
要是被贵族发现 我们就吃不完兜着走
Then pray that they don't.
那就祈祷他们不会发现
A.Knight`s.Tale.
骑士传说
Visor.
面甲拉下
Come on,we're late.
快点 我们迟了
The score stands at three lances to none in favor of Sir Ector.
目前比数是三比零 艾克特爵士领先
Lord Philip of Aragon.
阿拉贡的菲力浦勋爵
Stand ye ready?
您准备好了吗？
Sir Ector. Stand ye ready?
艾克特爵士 您准备好了吗？
Ready?
准备好了吗？
I tilted against Sir Ector many times.
我跟艾克特爵士对打过很多次
In practice as his target. You never strucK him.
当他的练习靶 你从来没击中他
- Badger me not with details.  - The landscape. Stay on the horse.
- 别拿这些细节来烦我  - 为了食物 千万别摔下马
He needs 3 points. He has to KnocK you off the horse.
他需要三分 他必须把你打下马
I Know how to score,Roland.
洛伦 我知道怎么记分
I've waited my whole life for this moment.
我这辈子等的就是这一刻
For Sir Ector to shite himself to death?
等艾克特爵爷死翘翘？
Get it in the cradle. In the cradle.
插进托架 托架
Get it in the cradle!
插进托架啊！
William,are you alive?
威廉 你还活着吗？
- We won! We won! - Can you hear me?
- 我们赢了！  - 你听得到我说话吗？
Get off me! William,can you hear me?
走开啦！ 威廉 你听得到吗？
We won!
我们赢了！
He's breathing. He's breathing!
他在呼吸 他还有气！
Sir Ector.
艾克特爵士
Sir Ector. Remove your helmet.
艾克特爵士 取下头盔
My lord,the final blow of the lance has bent it onto my head.
大人 最后一击 让我的头盔变形拿不下来了
He says the final blow of the
他说最后一击
I present your champion,my lord.
大人 这位就是优胜者
Twenty.
二十
No,10.
不 十
- Fifteen.  - Done.
- 十五  - 好
Very good. Cheers.
很好 再见了
Fifteen silver florins. He didn't want that.
十五个银币 他不要那个
That's five for William.
五个给威廉
Five for Wat. Five for Roland,who's going home to England.
五个给华特 另外五个 给要回英格兰老家的洛伦
Straight to the pub for me. Eel pie,brie tart
我要直接去酒馆 鳗鱼派、乳酪饼
tansy caKes with peppermint cream.
薄荷夹心的艾菊蛋糕
We could do this.
我们办得到
We've done it,boy. That's silver in your hand.
我们已经办到了 在你手上的可是银币啊
No,I mean,we can do this. We can be champions.
我是说我们可以靠比赛吃饭 我们可以打遍天下
Give us your coins.
把银币给我
Give me your coins.
快把银币给我
Now,that's one for you.
好 一个给你
And onefor you.
一个给你
Which leaves 13.
这样就剩下十三个
That's 1 3 for training and outfitting.
当作训练和治装的费用
The tournament in Rouen is in a month.
再一个月就是鲁昂枪术比赛
We could split a bigger prize.
我们可以共享更大的奖
In one month we'd be on our way to glory and riches.
再一个月我们就可以名利双收
Or lying in a ditch with Sir Ector. William,I just want to go home.
或跟艾克特爵士一样去见阎王 威廉 我只想回家
Tansy caKes. Dilled veal balls. I'll taKe my five now.
艾菊蛋糕和时萝小牛肉丸 我的五个银币给我
Oh,wait up.
等等
You're going the wrong way!
你走错路了！
You can't even joust.
你根本不会马上枪术比赛
Most of it is the guts to taKe a blow. Guts I have.
只要够胆准备被痛击就行了 我胆子够大
And technique? I have a month to learn that.
至于技巧呢？ 我有一个月的时间可以学
And name a man better with a sword than I am.
告诉我谁比我还会使剑
- In the practice ring.  - You're not of noble birth.
- 那是在练习的时候  - 你没有贵族血统
So,we lie.
那就骗他们啊
How did the nobles become noble in the first place?
贵族一开始 是怎么成为贵族的？
They tooK it at the tip of a sword. I'll do it with a lance.
他们在剑尖下受勋 我就用长枪来受勋
- A blunted lance.  - No matter,Wat.
- 一支钝枪  - 华特 那无所谓
A man can change his stars. I won't spend the rest of my life as nothing.
命运可以改变 我才不要一辈子默默无闻
That is nothing. And that's where glory will taKe us.
那才叫没没无闻 那就是想要名利双收的下场
We're peasants. Glory and riches are beyond our grasp.
我们只是平民 名利不是我们能享受的
But a full stomach? That dream can come true.
但是把肚子喂饱？ 这种梦才可能实现
If you can taKe your coins,go eat caKe in England.
如果你们能拿走银币 就去英格兰吃蛋糕吧
But if you can't,you come with me.
如果不能 就跟我走
You see? Money doesn't matter.
瞧吧 钱并不重要
See how hungry I am?!
看到我有多饿了吗？
- Do you?!  - Damn your stomach,Wat!
- 看到了吗？  - 华特 去你的肚子
Roland,please.
洛伦 拜托你
With 13 silver pieces,three men can change their stars.
利用十三个银币 三个男人可以改变他们的命运
God love you,William.
威廉 上帝爱你
I Know,I Know. No one else will.
我知道 我是爹不疼娘不爱
UnlucKy.
运气不好
- I thinK he's getting worse.  - He is getting worse.
- 他好像愈来愈糟了  - 他是愈来愈糟
Switch.
换手
Glory and riches. Glory and riches!
名利双收 名利双收！
You see how dangerous it is?
你知道多危险了吧？
Faster! Faster! All right,use those legs!
快一点！ 快一点！ 好好发挥你的脚力！
Come on,Roland. Faster! Faster!
快啊 洛伦！ 再快点！
You missed it.
你没击中
You've done it dozens of times.
你已经练习几十遍了
Well,I guess that means we should do it again.
我想那表示我们应该再来一次
Come on.
来吧
Come on,ponies.
快啊 小马儿
Fong him.
给他好看
Faster. Balance.
快一点 保持平衡
No,slower. Keep it steady.
不 慢一点 稳一点
I got it! Look,I got it!
我穿过去了！ 瞧 我穿过去了！
Any minute now.
就快了
- Yes,better.  - Nice.
- 比较好了  - 不错
- It's my turn to ride.  - No.
- 换我骑了  - 不
We haven't reached the marKer. And you shouldn't.
我们还没到指定的地方 而且你不该骑
How would it looK if my squire rode while I walKed?
我的随从骑马 我却走路 这样能看吗？
I don't give a witch's teat! It's my turn! It's my turn!
我才不管！ 该我骑了！ 该我骑了！
Maybe nobody should ride. The horse is not what he used to be.
也许大家都不该骑 这匹马体力不比从前了
Fine. Fine.
好吧
Morning.
早
Hoy,sir.
先生
What are you doing?
您在做什么？
Uhtrudging.
呃 跋涉
You Know,trudging? To trudge?
你知道跋涉吧？ 跋涉啊？
To trudge the slow,weary
缓慢、疲惫、沮丧
depressing,yet determined walK of a man who had nothing left
却意志坚定地走着 我什么都不剩
except the impulse to simply soldier on.
只剩下继续向前迈进的冲动
Were you robbed?
你被抢了吗？
Interesting question. Yes.
有意思的问题 是的
And at the same time,a huge,resounding,"No."
同时呢 我也要大声地说¨不是〃
It's more a sort of involuntary vow of poverty,really.
其实 这比较像是 非自愿性的贫穷
But on the brighter side,trudging does represent pride.
但往好的一面看 跋涉代表着自豪
Pride,resolve and faith in the good Lord Almighty.
自豪、果断 全心相信全知全能的上帝
Please,Christ,rescue me from my tribu-
基督啊 求求您 拯救我免于苦
lations.
难
Who are you?
你是谁？
Lilium inter spinas.
荆棘里的百合
The lily among the thorns.
Geoffrey Chaucer's the name. Writing's the game.
姓乔瑟名杰佛瑞 以写作为业
Chaucer?
乔瑟？
Geoffrey Chaucer,the writer?
杰佛瑞乔瑟 作家啊？
- A what?  - "A what?" A writer.
- 作什么？  - “作什么？” 作家
I write with inK and parchment. For a penny,I'll scribble anything.
我以墨水在羊皮纸上书写 给我一文钱 我什么都帮你写
Summonses,decrees,edicts,warrants,patents of nobility.
召集令、法令、诏书 授权书、贵族血统证明
I've been Known to jot down a poem,if the muse descends.
我还以写诗闻名 如果有灵感的话
You probably read my booK,The Book of the Duchess.
你们大概看过我的书 公爵夫人之书
Well,it was allegorical.
那是个寓言
We won't hold it against you. Each man decides that for himself.
我们不会因此对你有成见的 每个人都有权自作决定
Did you say patents of nobility?
你刚说贵族血统证明吗？
That's right. I did.
没错 我是这么说的
And you gentlemen are?
你们三位是？
I am Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein from Gelderland.
我是乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士 来自盖德兰
These are my faithful squires,Delves of Dodgington
他们是我忠心的随从 道京顿的戴夫
and Fowlehurst of Crewe.
还有克鲁伊的佛赫斯特
I'm Richard the Lionheart. A pleasure.
我是狮心理察 幸会
No,I'm Charlemagne! John the Baptist!
不 我是查理大帝！ 施洗者约翰！
All right!
好了！
Hold your tongue,sir,or lose it.
闭嘴 否则我让你开不了口
Now you see that,I do believe
说真的 我相信你
Sir Ulrich.
乌瑞克爵士
ThanK you
谢谢你
Geoff.
杰夫
Have you any more to say,Master Nude,or may we be on our way?
赤裸大师 你还有话要说 或者我们可以上路了？
- Off to the tournament?  - This is the road to Rouen.
- 去枪术比赛？  - 这条是到鲁昂的路
That remains to be seen. They're limiting the field at Rouen.
那还不一定呢 鲁昂那里限制得很严
Noble birth must be established for four generations on either side.
父母双方四代都是贵族 才会被认定是贵族
Patents of nobility must be provided.
还要附贵族血统证明书
Listen,clothe me
听着 只要给我衣服
shoe me,for God's saKe,feed me and you'll have your patents.
给我鞋子 喂饱我 你的证明书就不成问题
No.
不
- Patents of nobility.  - We need him. We need him.
- 贵族血统证明书  - 我们需要他
- Let me handle it.  - Be nice.
- 我来处理  - 好声好气点
Nice,nice,nice.
好声好气 好声好气
All right.
好
Betray us and I will fong you until your insides are out
你要是敢背叛我们 我就打得你吐破肠流
your outsides are in and your entrails are your extrails.
面目全非 内脏变外脏
Pain.
我会让你痛苦
Lots of pain.
非常痛苦
比赛大会会场 鲁昂
I present Sir Ulrich,whose mother's father was Shilhard von Rechberg
为您介绍乌瑞克爵士 其外祖父为席拉德冯瑞克堡
son of the DuKe Guelph of Saxony,son of Ghibellines,son of Wendish.
曾祖为萨克森的顾尔夫公爵 曾曾祖纪林 曾曾曾祖温狄胥
- Wendish inherited the fief  - That'll do,herald.
- 而温狄胥继承了  - 可以了 传令人
Six generations is more than enough. Show me the patents.
六代很够了 证明书给我看
Indicate in which events shall your Lord Ulrich compete.
指出你的乌瑞克大人 要参加哪几场比赛
He'll first meet Roger Lord Mortimer.
他第一场出战的是摩提莫大人
ThanK you very much.
非常谢谢你
I can't believe it. You did it,Chaucer.
真不敢相信 乔瑟 你做到了
I thanK you. I didn't thinK we had a chance.
我得谢谢你 我本来不认为 我们会有机会
My pleasure,William.
威廉 我很乐意帮忙
If you don't mind,I'll sticK around.
你不介意的话 我想留下来
Be my herald,you'll get part of the winnings.
当我的传令人吧 我赢的话你也有份
Done. Now if you don't mind,I have to see a man about a dog.
说定了 现在请容我离开 我必须去找一个人谈生意
Walking out from Cheapside
离开了奇普塞
My fortunes for to seek
寻找大好前程
I passed along the River Thames
我走过泰晤士河畔
Its Waters did they reek
河水臭气冲天
"Was there I met a pretty lass
我在那儿遇见一位美丽姑娘
She said her name Was Nell
她说她名叫妮尔
Bell or hell rhymes with Nell.
不管天堂地狱 我都跟她去
Would you speaK to me?
你愿意跟我说话吗？
Ah,to speaK.
说话啊
Sir,my sex are marKed by their silence.
先生 女人不该多话的
I would hear you speaK if it cost me my ears.
我很想听你说话 即使我会因此失去双耳
That is well,for I do not want silence in my life.
很好 因为我可不希望 一生沉默无语
Tell me your name.
告诉我你叫什么名字
- Would you care if I were ugly?  - Yes
- 若我很丑 你还会在乎吗？  - 会
I mean,no. I mean
我是说不会 我是说
You desecrate the house of God!
你亵渎了上帝的居所！
Tell me your name.
告诉我你的名字
And what would you do with my name,Sir Hunter?
你要拿我的名字做什么呢 猎人先生？
Call me a fox,for that is all I am to you.
叫我狐狸吧 我对你而言不过如此
Then a fox you shall be until I find your name,my foxy lady.
性感美女 那我就先叫你狐狸 直到我问出你的名字
He's a handsome hunter. I give him that.
我承认他这猎人挺英俊的
Does this not shocK you,ladies?
小姐们 你们不震惊吗？
Certainly,my lord.
当然震惊啊 大人
I only laugh just to Keep from weeping.
我笑是因为怕自己哭出来
Beauty is such a curse.
美貌真是诅咒啊
Pray your years come swiftly.
祈祷你年华早逝
Pray your beauty fades so you may better serve God.
花容尽褪 好更尽心服侍上帝
Oh,I do,my lord. I pray for it all the time.
我有啊 我常常这么祈祷
Why,God,did you curse me with this face?
上帝啊 你为何诅咒我 给我这张脸？
God's will has a purpose,but we may not Know it.
上帝自有他的道理 但我们可能无从得知
Well,that is lovely.
这真好看
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士
defeats Roger Lord Mortimer one lance to none.
打败摩提莫大人 比数是一比零
Easy. They'll thinK l never broKe a lance before.
真简单 他们会以为 我从来没打赢过
- But you haven't!  - Ulrich's broKen thousands of lances.
- 你是没打赢过啊！  - 乌瑞克赢过数千次
Come on. You're due in the sword ring.
走吧 该去比剑了
My armor's loose.
我的盔甲松了
Shite. I can't blocK an overhead.
可恶 我会挡不住上方的攻击
We can't fix it now. We're overdue in the sword ring.
现在来不及修了 我们比剑已经迟到了
It was a mistaKe to do two events. I'm too hurried.
不该比两种的 太赶了
- I'll withdraw from the sword.  - Sword's what you're best at.
- 我退出比剑好了  - 剑术是你最拿手的
But the prizes and prestige are bigger in the joust.
但是比长枪的奖赏比较丰富 名声也比较响亮
Ulrich von Lichtenstein? I am Simon the Summoner.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦？ 我是传唤者赛门
I'm overdue at the sword ring.
而我比剑快迟到了
I must detain you on behalf of your herald.
我谨代表你的传令人留下你
You Were never robbed.
你才没有被抢
I have a gambling problem.
我有酗赌的问题
I can't help myself.
我控制不了自己
And these people will
而这些人真的会
Iiterally taKe the clothes off your bacK.
剥光你的衣服
What are we supposed to do?
你要我们怎么办？
He assured us that you,his liege,would pay us.
他跟我们保证他的主人 也就是你 会付我们钱
And who are you?
你是什么人来着？
Peter,a humble pardoner
彼得 卑微的免罪符小贩
and purveyor of religious relics.
和宗教遗物供应商
How much does he owe?
他欠了多少钱？
Ten gold florins.
十个金币
You manKy git!
你这蠢蛋
- Pain! Pain! TaKe the pain!  - Get him off me!
- 痛吧 痛死好了  - 快把他拉开
Wat,let him go!
华特 放开他
What would you do to him if I was to refuse?
如果我不付钱 你会对他怎样？
We,on behalf of the Lord God
我们会谨代表上帝
will taKe it from his flesh so that he may understand
要他用命来还 好让他了解
that gambling is a sin.
赌博是有罪的
Oh,come on.
别这样
Please,Will.
威廉 求求你
Please,will you help me,Sir Ulrich?
求你帮我好吗 乌瑞克爵士？
I promise you won't regret it.
我保证你不会后悔的
I don't have the money.
我没那么多钱
Release him
放了他
and give him bacK his clothes.
把衣服还他吧
And you'll get it.
你们会拿到钱的
Done.
没问题
You lied.
你说谎
Yes,I lied. I'm a writer. I give the truth scope!
对 我说谎 我是作家 我对真话的定义很广泛
Behold my Lord Ulrich von Lichtenstein,son of
看哪 我的乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦大人
- Too late. He's been announced.  - Fine.
- 太迟了 他要出场了  - 好吧
Ten blows by sword. Sir Ulrich to receive first.
先击中十下者为胜 先由乌瑞克爵士受击
StriKe!
击中了
Stop letting him hit you!
别再让他打中你了
Shut up! Shut up!
闭嘴 闭嘴
Two striKes for Sir Walter Loring!
沃特罗令爵士得两分
Sir Ulrich to striKe!
换乌瑞克爵士出剑！
- Now it's your turn!  - Come on!
- 该你了  - 加油！
StriKe!
击中了
I taught him that! That's me!
那是我教他的！ 是我教他的！
Sir Ulrich prevails,five striKes to two!
乌瑞克爵士以五比二获胜！
Yes!
好耶！
Behold my Lord Ulrich! The rocK! The hard place!
看哪 我的乌瑞克大人！ 他稳若磐石 耸立如泰山！
LiKe a wind from Gelderland,he sweeps by!
他像盖德兰来的一阵风 横扫而过！
Blown far from his homeland in search of glory and honor!
从他的家乡吹袭过来 寻求胜利和荣耀！
We walK in the garden of his turbulence!
我们行走在他引发的骚动中！
Yeah!
好耶！
- You're champion.  - Of the sword.
- 你是冠军  - 剑术之冠
Isn't that why we're here? Come on.
我们不就是为此而来吗？ 走吧
Do you want to touch him? Do you want to touch him?
想碰碰他吗？ 你们想碰碰他吗？
We should've saved our money for the blacKsmith.
我们应该留点钱修盔甲的
I can't pay you noW
我现在没钱付你
- but I promise I will,just as  - No! Money.
- 但我保证会付 只要  - 不行！ 钱
- Excuse me.  - Cash first,not promises.
- 请问一下  - 拿钱来再说 光说没用
Go on.
离开吧
Excuse me,sir.
先生 请问一下
You might try the farris.
去蹄铁匠那里试试吧
A woman?
女的？
Beggars cannot be choosers,my lord.
大人 乞丐是没得选的
ThanK you.
谢谢
- Excuse me.  - I don't worK for free.
- 请问一下  - 我不做白工
- I can't joust with broKen armor.  - That's your problem,not mine.
- 盔甲破损我无法比赛  - 那是你的问题 不是我的
Each drop of this sweat has a price on it.
我流的每一滴汗都有价钱
Just as well. They told me I was daft to even asK.
好吧 他们叫我 别傻到来问你
- Who? - The other armorers.
- 谁？  - 其他的盔甲匠
Did they say I couldn't do it because I'm a woman?
他们是不是说我修不好 因为我是女人？
They said you're good with horseshoes,not armor.
他们说你擅长的是马蹄铁 不是盔甲
No one mentioned you being a woman.
没人提什么女人不女人的
Cat's meat! Hot Wine!
猫肉！ 热酒！
Lady,I will win this tournament for you.
小姐 我会为你 赢得这场锦标赛的
Nay! I will win for you.
不！ 是我会为你而赢
May I present Count Adhemar
容我介绍阿德玛伯爵
winner of the joust in France and champion at Saint- Emilion.
法国长枪赛的优胜者 圣埃米里翁大赛的冠军
All forgotten when standing before the most beautiful woman in Christendom.
在基督教世界最美的女子面前 那一切都无足轻重了
Do you only pretend to fight,Count Adhemar,or wage real war as well?
伯爵 你只是装个样子 或是真的在打仗？
I am leader of the free companies. My army is in southern France.
我是自由连队的领导人 我的军队在法国南部
Geoff,it's my lady.
杰夫 那就是我仰慕的女人
- William,you aim too high.  - I don't Know any other way to aim.
- 威廉 你目标定太高了  - 我没有其他的目标了
- Concentrate.  - What should I say to her?
- 专心  - 我该跟她说些什么？
What do you thinK of the joust?
你对枪术比赛有何看法？
It's very abrupt.
非常唐突
And I don't understand the rules.
规则我也不了解
Then I shall educate you.
那就让我来教你
A match is three lances.
一场比赛分三回合
One point is given for breaKing a lance between the waist and necK.
击中对手腰颈之间而断枪 得一分
Two points for breaKing on the helmet. It's difficult.
击落面甲而断枪 得两分 这很困难
The helmet sweeps bacK. Most blows glance off.
面甲会弹回来 所以多半只是一闪而过
Three points for bearing a rider to the ground.
让对手落地得三分
Also,if you bear a rider to the ground,you win his horse.
而且 如果你让对手落地 他的马就是你的了
Do men die in the joust?
有人在枪术比赛中丧命吗？
Lance points are tipped with coronals,which blunts them.
长枪头是装上了冠状的钝器
Of course,accidents happen.
当然 难免会有意外
I myself,Jocelyn,have never been unhorsed.
约瑟琳 而我本身从未落马过
Nor have l.
我也是
Your name,lady.
小姐 您的大名
I still need to hear it.
我还是需要知道
Sir Hunter,you persist.
猎人先生 你还真坚持
Perhaps angels have no names. Only beautiful faces.
或许天使没有名字 只有美丽的脸庞
And you are?
请问你是？
I am,um.
我是 嗯
Have you forgotten?
你忘了吗？
Or your name is Sir "Um."
或者你就叫“嗯”爵士
Ulrich von Lichtenstein from Gelderland.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦 来自盖德兰
I'd forget as well. What a mouthful.
我也会记不住 真难念啊
- Your armor,sir.  - What about it?
- 先生 您的盔甲  - 怎么样？
How stylish of you to wear an antique. You'll start a new fashion if you win.
您真时髦 穿这么件古董 若您获胜 定会创造新风潮
My grandfather will be able to wear his in public again.
那样我祖父就能 再度穿他的旧衣外出了
And a shield. How quaint.
还有盾牌 多有趣啊
Some of these poor country Knights,little better than peasants.
有些穷乡僻壤的骑士 只比平民好一点点
the second son
华勒斯
of Sir Wallace Percival,third Earl of WarwicK.
普西佛爵士 沃里克的第三伯爵的二公子
My lords,my ladies
各位大人、小姐
it is with honor I introduce my liege
很荣幸向各位介绍 我的主人
Sir Thomas Colville.
汤玛斯寇维尔爵士
You're good.
你很行
You're very good.
你非常行
My lords
各位大人
my ladies
各位小姐
and everybody else here not sitting on a cushion
以及其他 没有座位的诸位
today
今天
you find yourselves equals.
在场的各位是平等的
For you are all equally blessed.
因为你们同样都受到神佑
For I have the pride
因为我很自豪
the privilege,nay,the pleasure
很荣幸 不 是很高兴
of introducing to you a Knight sired by Knights.
位各位介绍一位 由骑士世家出身的骑士
A Knight who can trace his lineage bacK
他的血统可追溯至
beyond Charlemagne.
查理曼大帝之前的时代
I first met him
我初次遇见他
atop a mountain near Jerusalem
是在耶路撒冷附近的山顶
praying to God
他向上帝祈祷
asKing his forgiveness for the Saracen blood
请他原谅他剑上沾满了
spilt by his sword.
撒拉逊人的血
Next,he amazed me still further in Italy
接着 在意大利 他更令我觉得不可思议
when he saved a fatherless beauty
当他拯救一位失怙的孤女
from the would be ravishings of her dreadful uncle.
免于她恶叔父的残害
In Greece
在希腊
he spent a year in silence
他保持缄默一年
just to better understand the sound
只为求更加了解
of a whisper.
轻声细语
So without further gilding the lily and with no more ado
我就不再锦上添花 也不再多费唇舌
I give to you the SeeKer of Serenity
我要介绍给各位 安详平静的追寻者
Protector of Italian Virginity
意大利贞节的保护者
the Enforcer of our Lord God,the one,the only
上帝旨意的执行者 独一无二的
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein!
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士！
ThanK you! ThanK you! I'll be here all weeK.
谢谢 谢谢各位！ 我整个星期都会在这里
That was different.
真与众不同啊
It's time we celebrated our differences.
是我们颂扬每个人 独特之处的时候了
Just maybe not in public.
只要不在公开场合
You.
你
Yes,I'm well aware a good fonging is on the way.
是的 我很清楚 我很快就会被好好修理了
Oh,yeah. Oh,yeah.
对 没错
I got their attention. You win their hearts.
我负责引他们注意 你去赢得他们的心
Very good.
非常好
Was she watching? Geoff. What?
- 杰夫 她刚刚有看吗？  - 什么？
- Did she see me?  - Yes,she did.
- 她看了我吗？  - 是的
- Did she see me taKe the hit?  - Yes.
- 她看到我受击？  - 是的
- Was she concerned?  - Her eyes welled up. Just awful.
- 她担心吗？  - 她眼泪盈眶 太糟了
Colville has perfect technique. I've never seen him before.
寇维尔技巧很完美 我以前从未见过他
Nor I.
我也是
But this Lichtenstein.
但这个利顿斯坦
His technique,rudimentary. Style,nonexistent.
他的技巧只在入门阶段 风格更是完全不存在
Still,he's fearless.
然而 他无所畏惧
Fearless? How so?
无所畏惧？ 怎么说？
The slit in the visor is narrow,but splinters can penetrate it.
面甲里的缝隙很窄 但碎木片可以穿透其间
Most Knights raise their chins at the last instant.
大多数骑士在最后一瞬间 都会抬起下巴
You lose sight of your opponent,but protect your eyes. Ulrich doesn't.
虽看不到对手 却能保护双眼 乌瑞克则否
He Keeps his eye on the target.
他眼睛牢牢盯着目标
A true hunter.
不折不扣的猎人
Sir Ulrich
乌瑞克爵士
I'm through.
我要退出了
But I've never not finished before.
但我以前从未中途退出
I wish to Keep my honor intact.
我希望完整保持我的荣誉
A draw. And Colville is hurt.
不分胜负 寇维尔受伤了
Colville withdraws. Ulrich advances.
寇维尔退出 乌瑞克晋级
Why didn't Ulrich finish him?
乌瑞克为何不乘胜追击？
He shows mercy.
他慈悲为怀
Then he shows his weaKness. That's all mercy is.
那么他就展露了弱点 慈悲只会使人脆弱
For the love of victory,William,go to sleep.
威廉 看在胜利的份上 快睡吧
I can't.
我睡不着
Love has given me wings,so I must fly.
爱情给了我翅膀 我必须飞翔
I can't explain it.
我无法解释
- She maKes me feel liKe a poet.  - You may feel liKe a poet
- 她让我自觉像个诗人 - 你或许自觉像诗人
but you sound liKe an idiot.
但你听起来像个白痴
- You don't even Know her name.  - Her name?
- 你连她的名字都不知道  - 她的名字？
Her name is Aphrodite.
她叫爱芙萝黛蒂
Calypso. Venus. TaKe your picK.
卡丽普索、维纳斯 随你选
Women weaKen the heart.
女人让人意志软弱
Without your heart,you cannot win.
没有了意志 你就无法获胜
- But her eyes  - Concentrate.
- 但她的眼睛  - 专心
Tansy caKes!
艾菊蛋糕！
Count Adhemar sends Word.
阿德玛伯爵派人来传话
He said he will win this tournament for you.
他说他会为你赢得这场锦标赛
He's won many. He wins them for himself and his own honor.
他已赢过许多次 他是为他自己和他的荣誉而赢
It's nothing to say he wins them for me.
他这么说是毫无价值的
He wishes to speaK to you again.
他希望能再次跟您谈谈
Not to hear a word I say.
而不是听我说话
Adhemar wants his women silent.
阿德玛要他的女人保持沉默
Would you have Sir Ulrich win the tournament for you?
你会要乌瑞克爵士 为你赢得这场锦标赛吗？
No.
不
And he is the only Knight who has not promised to do so.
他是唯一一个 未许诺要这么做的骑士
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士
I would have him win my heart.
我要他赢得我的心
Adhemar! Adhemar! Adhemar!
阿德玛！ 阿德玛！ 阿德玛！
Oh,lovely.
真帅啊
I don't thinK I've ever seen Count Adhemar lose.
我不认为我看过阿德玛伯爵输
No,but defeat him and you'll see it firsthand.
的确 但打败了他 你就会第一个看到
My liege
我的主人
Sir Ulrich.
乌瑞克爵士
Christiana.
这位是克丽丝堤亚娜
- My lady bids you wear this toKen.  - Of course.
- 我家小姐吩咐你戴上这个  - 当然
She also said to tell you,her name
她还要我告诉你 她名叫
is Jocelyn.
约瑟琳
- Au revoir.  - Au revoir.
- 再会  - 再会
Oh,Jocelyn.
约瑟琳
Concentrate.
专心比赛
I can't breathe.
我无法呼吸
No style whatsoever.
毫无风格可言
But neither has an anvil.
铁砧也是如此
- He hits like a hammer. Amazing.  - But not perfect. He aims high.
- 他出手真是惊人地有力  - 但是不完美 瞄得太高了
Roll your shoulder back,his blow may go right.
肩膀向后 他可能会往右边刺
But if he strikes to my left,I'll be obliterated.
但要是他往我左边刺 我就毁了
I didn't say it wasn't a gamble.
我没说这不是场赌博
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
William?
威廉？
William,here.
威廉 这里
Come here.
过来这里
Someday I'll be a knight.
总有一天我会成为骑士
A thatcher's son? A knight?
补屋顶工匠家的孩子？ 骑士？
You might as well try to change the stars.
你还不如试着改变命运呢
Can it be done,Father?
父亲 有可能吗？
- Can a man change the stars?  - Yes,William.
- 人可以改变命运吗？  - 可以的 威廉
If he believes enough,a man can do anything.
如果一个人信心坚定 他可以成就任何事情
Come here.
来
Gain more bearing,Ulrich.
乌瑞克 再去锻炼锻炼吧
See me again when you're worthy.
等你够资格了再来见我
I'll fong you in the arse!
我非要你好看不可！
Well done,my lord! Well done.
大人 精采啊 真精采
- You bastard!  - Go and see to Ulrich.
- 你这混帐  - 快去看看乌瑞克
Go see to Ulrich.
去看看乌瑞克
Well done,my lord.
大人 漂亮
A noble victory.
赢得真高尚
My lady,I believe this is yours.
小姐 这应该是你的
For long spear on foot
长矛的优胜者是
Pandolfo Malatesta.
潘多佛马拉泰斯塔
For sword on foot,Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
剑术的优胜者是 乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦
Finally,for the mounted joust and tournament champion
最后 马上枪术以及锦标赛的 冠军是
Adhemar,Count of Anjou.
安竺的阿德玛伯爵
Adhemar! Adhemar! Adhemar!
阿德玛！ 阿德玛！ 阿德玛！
I present to you your champions.
这几位就是优胜者
Next time,you will look up at me from the flat of your back.
下一次 你会躺在地上 仰望着我
Please. You have been weighed,
拜托 你打也打了 比也比了
you have been measured
大家都知道你能力不足
Keep winning the sword.
继续保持剑术方面的战绩
- I won't compete in it.  - It's your best.
- 我不比剑了 - 那是你最擅长的啊
No. It's tournament champion or nothing at all.
不 除非得到总冠军 否则什么都不算数
Ten florins. That should do.
十个银币 这应该够了
Sixes and sevens tonight,Chaucer. Do you feel lucky?
乔瑟 今晚还有得赌 觉得手气还顺吗？
- Have you enough clothes?  - Be gone. I'm done with you.
- 你衣服穿得够多吗？  - 滚吧 我不想再看到你们
Except to exact my revenge.
除了展开我的报复
What on earth could you possibly do to us?
你能对我们怎样？
I will eviscerate you in fiction.
我会在小说里把你们开膛剖腹
Every last pimple,every last character flaw.
把你们的丑恶和缺点 钜细靡遗地描述出来
I was naked for a day. You will be naked for eternity.
我曾经赤裸着身体一天 我要你们永生都赤身露体
I have a feeling we shall meet again.
我有预感我们会再见
Here,farris,take what we owe you.
蹄铁匠 这是我们欠你的
The armor you wear,it wasn't made for you,was it?
你身上穿的盔甲 不是为你订制的吧？
So?
那又怎样？
I could make armor you wouldn't even know you wore it.
我可以做出让你 甚至感觉不到重量的盔甲
What's the cost?
那要多少钱？
Just take me as far as Paris.
只要带我到巴黎就好
We travel alone. Take your gold and go.
我们不需要伴 拿着你的金块走吧
- Get what you can. Let's pack.  - Why are we leaving so soon?
- 能拿的尽量拿 快打包吧  - 你干嘛这么急着走？
The next tournament is in a week. We can walk now and save the horse.
离下一场大赛只剩一周 现在走 才能让马休息
You must go to the banquet. You'll dance and make an appearance.
你必须参加庆祝会 跳舞、跟大家认识
Let Adhemar laugh at me again? No!
让阿德玛再次嘲笑我？ 不
- Yes!  - No!
- 要  - 不！
My lady would know the color of your lord's tunic tonight.
我家小姐想知道 你家主人今晚外衣的颜色
- His tunic?  - Yes,so she can dress to match him.
- 他的外衣？  - 是的 她好穿相搭的颜色
We regret to inform your lady he won't be attending- -
我们很遗憾必须告诉你家小姐 他不会参加
- Herald,do not give my answers!  - Yes,my lord.
- 传令的 你别代我回答  - 是的 大人
Squire,answer her.
随从 回答她
What color is my tunic tonight?
我今晚的外衣是什么颜色？
Green.
绿色
Trimmed in a kind of
滚边用
pale green
淡淡的绿
with
配上
uh,wooden toggles.
木质系扣
I will tell my lady.
我会转告我家小姐
- This is a disaster!  - No,it'll tunic up quite nicely.
- 完蛋了  - 不 这样很好
That's not a disaster,Roland.
洛伦 我不是说外衣
I don't know how to dance.
我不会跳舞
And one and two and three and four.
一 二 三 四
Your hand should be light,like a birdie on a branch.
手要轻一点 像停在枝头上的鸟儿
And one,two and three and four.
一 二 三 四
And Wat doesn't lead,he follows like a girl.
华特不许带舞 他跳得像女孩子似的
And one and two and
一 二
twirly,twirly,twirly.
旋转 旋转 旋转
And one and two,and you're still getting it wrong.
一 二 你还是没跳对
And one and two and three and four.
一 二 三 四
You can hit me all day because you punch like a what?
你可以打我一整天 因为你的力道像什么？
A girl.
女孩子
- Enough!  - Get back! Wat,quiet!
- 够了！  - 回去！ 华特 安静！
- He starts it.  - You know he's touchy!
- 是他开始的  - 你明知道他很暴躁！
Oh,and you can do better?
难道你可以教得更好？
- Of course.  - Then show us.
- 当然  - 那就让我们瞧瞧
No.
不
If I'm making all this effort,you'd best ask her nicely.
我都这么尽心尽力了 你最好礼貌地拜托她
I'm sorry,Kate.
凯蒂 对不起
I was wondering if you'd care to show us how to dance.
不知道你是否可以 教我们该怎么跳舞
- Please.  - Please.
- 拜托你 - 拜托啦
And one and two,three and four.
一 二 三 四
Five,six,seven,change partners.
五 六 七 换舞伴
And one,two,three,four
一 二 三 四
five,six,seven.
五 六 七
Polonaise. And one.
波洛奈兹舞
Are you wearing your hair like that?
你不会不整理头发就去吧？
Is there another way?
有其他的发型吗？
Sir Ulrich,you look fantastic.
乌瑞克爵士 你帅气极了
Jocelyn,you look.
约瑟琳 你看起来
Uh,you
呃 你
remind me of the Bible.
让我联想到圣经
When God stopped the sun to give Joshua time to defeat the Amorites.
当上帝让太阳静止 好让约书亚打败亚摩利人
I don't understand.
我不明白
If I could ask God one thing
若我能求上帝一件事
it would be to stop the moon.
那就是让月亮静止
Stop the moon and make this night
让月亮静止 让这个夜晚
and your beauty
和你的美丽
Iast forever.
持续到永远
What dance will you have? A coranto?
你要跳哪种舞？ 库朗特舞？
Or a basse dance?
或是低步舞？
Sir Ulrich.
乌瑞克爵士
Why don't you show us a dance of your country?
你何不让我们看看 贵国的舞步？
Show us a dance of Gelderland.
让我们看看盖德兰的舞步
Yes. Gelderland.
是的 盖德兰
Well,it's a lot like the farandole
那很像法兰多拉舞
but with some differences.
但有些不同
Well,you bow.
先鞠躬
And
然后
and.
Places. Places.
各位请就定位
What?
怎么了？
- I don't know. Too small,too light.  - He'll be crushed. Killed.
- 我不知道 太小太轻了  - 他会被打扁 打到死翘翘
No. I found a new way to heat steel. It's thinner,smaller
不会 我发现炼钢的新方法 做起来比较薄 比较小
but just as strong.
但是一样坚固
What are these?
这是什么？
The marks of my trade should another knight admire the armor.
我的商标 以备有其他骑士 喜欢我做的盔甲
Twist and bend. Feel the movement.
活动活动 感受它的轻巧
- But eventually I will be struck.  - And then death.
- 但我终究会被击中  - 然后死掉
Do you at least have the courage to test it?
你有勇气测试看看吗？
You okay?
你还好吗？
I didn't feel a thing.
我什么感觉都没有
枪术比赛会场 拉格尼叙马恩
- Who's that knight?  - Piers Courtenay.
- 那位骑士是谁？  - 皮耶寇特尼
He's raised taxes on his land 3 times this year to pay for tournament.
他为了筹款参加枪术比赛 今年已经提高税收三次了
His people starve while he sits at banquet.
他的人民在挨饿受苦 他却在大肆庆祝
It's probably true.
很有可能是真的吧
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦
The Count Adhemar
阿德玛伯爵
son of Philippe de Vitry
菲利浦德维崔之子
son of Gilles
吉尔之孙
master of the free companies
自由连队的领导者
defender of his enormous manhood
雄壮威武的卫冕者
a shining example of chivalry
骑士精神的良好楷模
and champagne.
还有香槟
Nice work!
说得好！
Bravo!
精采极了！
Watch every move Adhemar makes. We'll find a weakness.
仔细观察阿德玛的动作 找出他的弱点
Well,Colville looks fit.
寇维尔看起来状况很好
my liege
我的主人
the second son of Sir Wallace Percival.
华特斯普西佛爵士二公子
It is my deepest honor
我谨以最深的敬意
My deepest honor to present to you.
以我最深的敬意向各位介绍
It's Edward,my lord. They're sure of it.
大人 是爱德华 他们很肯定
the illustrious Sir Thomas Colville!
显赫的汤玛斯寇维尔爵士！
Adhemar withdrew.
阿德玛退出比赛了
To withdraw like that means one thing.
会那样退出只代表一件事
Royalty.
皇室
I'll see what I can find out.
我去打听看看
Prepare to drop the flag.
准备降旗
No,no. Not yet. Wait,listen.
不 还不要 等等 听着
Musicians,announce.
乐手们 快吹号
- I must speak with my lord.  - Then go.
- 我有事跟我主人报告  - 那就去吧
See if you can beat the Second Coming.
看你能否快过基督复临
Wait! Wait!
慢着！ 等等！
Colville is Edward,the Black Prince,future king of England.
寇维尔就是黑王子爱德华 英格兰的王储
He's in disguise like me so he can compete.
他跟我一样 为了参赛而掩饰身份
He's never met an enemy without victory or town he couldn't defeat.
他每战必胜 攻无不克
We're English! We know who he is!
我们是英国人！ 我们知道！
- You must withdraw. Tell them,Geoff.  - Absolutely!
- 你必须退出 杰夫 告诉他们  - 那当然！
The lance.
长枪给我
Give me the lance.
把长枪给我
Lance!
长枪拿来！
Oh,my giddy aunt.
我的老天爷啊
The match is a draw.
这场比赛不分胜负
You mad? You endanger a royal family member.
你疯了吗？ 你差点伤了皇室成员
He endangers himself.
是他自己让自己置身危险
Well fought,Sir Ulrich,as in Rouen.
爵士 打得好 一如在鲁昂
You also,Prince Edward.
您也是 爱德华王子
You knew me?
你知道是我？
And still you rode?
但你还是上场比赛？
- It's not in me to withdraw.  - No. Nor me.
- 退出不是我的作风  - 我也一样
Though it happens.
虽然这种事常有
Yes,it does.
的确
- Good luck to you.  - You also.
- 祝你好运  - 您也是
The winner of the mounted joust and tournament champion
马上长枪大赛 和锦标赛的优胜者是
Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦
- Melt it,sell it,do whatever you do.  - Yes,Your Majesty.
- 要熔要卖都随你  - 是的 大人
You're champion!
你是冠军！
I'm not champion until I defeat Adhemar. He withdrew.
我还不是冠军 除非打败阿德玛 他中途退出
Sir Ulrich.
乌瑞克爵士
- Tell me what you'll wear tonight.  - Nothing.
- 告诉我你今晚要穿什么  - 什么都不穿
We'll cause a sensation,for I'll dress to match.
那么我们会引起骚动 因为我会配合你
Don't you get tired of putting on clothes?
你穿衣服穿得不烦吗？
She's talking about taking them off.
她说的是不要穿
A flower is only as good as its petals,no?
有花没有瓣也是没有用的 不是吗？
A flower is good for nothing.
花儿一点用处也没有
Really?
真的？
You can't eat a flower. It doesn't keep you warm.
花儿不能吃 也不能保暖
And a rose never knocked a man off a horse either,did it?
玫瑰也从来不曾 把男人击落马下 不是吗？
You're just a silly girl,aren't you?
你只是个蠢女孩 不是吗？
Better a silly girl with a flower than a silly boy with a horse and stick.
拿着花的蠢女孩 总好过骑马拿着棍棒的蠢男孩
Goodbye.
再见
It's called a lance.
那叫做长枪
Hello.
懂不懂啊
波尔多
- I have word.  - What?
- 我听到消息  - 什么？
Adhemar was called back to the free companies.
阿德玛被召回自由连队
Edward commanded it. He could be gone all season.
是爱德华下的令 他可能整季都不会回来
First Jocelyn and now Adhemar.
先是约瑟琳 现在又是阿德玛
well done.
说得真好
Yeah,well done.
是啊 说得好
南方前线 普瓦提耶战役
The tournament results,my lord.
大人 比赛结果在这里
Ulrich.
乌瑞克
- Geoff.  - William.
- 杰夫  - 威廉
I need to write a letter.
我需要写一封信
"Dear Jocelyn." No. "My dearest Jocelyn."
“亲爱的约瑟琳”不“挚爱的约瑟琳”
Better.
好多了
"I miss you."
“我想你”
Was that wrong?
那样不对吗？
Well,it's up to you,really. It's your funeral,I mean,letter.
其实要看你啦 这是你的告别式 我是说你的信
- Say something about her breasts.  - You miss them.
- 提提她的胸部  - 你想念他们
Her breasts?
她的胸部？
Yes,you could,but I would tend to look above her breasts.
是的 你可以 但要是我 就会看她胸部以上的地方
I miss her throat?
我想念她的喉咙？
Still higher. Towards the heavens.
再高一点 朝向天堂
The moon. Her breasts weren't that impressive.
月亮啊 她的双峰没那么让人印象深刻
The moon? The moon.
月亮？ 月亮啊
"It is strange to think
想起来实在奇怪
I have not seen you in a month.
我已经一个月没见你了
I have seen the new moon,but not you.
我见到了新月 却不见你
I have seen sunsets and sunrises,but nothing of your beautiful face."
我看到了日升日落 却未看到你美丽的容颜
That's very good.
非常好
I knew this girl once who.
我曾经认识一个女孩
She broke my heart. I said the pieces- -
她让我心碎 我说心的碎片
"The pieces of my broken heart can pass through the eye of a needle. "
“我说心的碎片 小的都可以穿过针孔了”
He writes as though I had died.
他写得好像我已经死了
Yes,madame. He dies as well.
是的 女士 他也像死了一样
She used to cook for the Duke of York.
她曾是约克公爵的厨子
I miss her like the sun misses the flower.
我对她的思念 就像太阳对花儿的思念
"I miss you like the sun misses the floWer."
我对你的思念 就像太阳对花儿的思念
Like the sun misses the flower in the depths of winter.
就像太阳在深冬 对花儿的思念
Instead of beauty to direct its light to
少了花儿的艳容 引导着阳光
the heart hardens like the frozen world your absence has sent me to.
心也就变得麻痹 就像你不在我身边般寒冷
I next compete in Paris.
我接下来会在巴黎出赛
I'll find it empty and cold if you're not there.
如果你不在那里 我会觉得空虚寒冷
I like it.
我喜欢
And now,to finish it.
现在 写结语吧
With "hope."
用“希望”
Love should end with hope.
爱应该以希望作结
My husband,God rest him
我丈夫 愿他安息
said something I'll never forget.
说了句我永远不会忘记的话
"Hope guides me. It "
“希望引导着我”
"It gets me through the day and especially the night.
让我得以度过白日 特别是夜晚
The hope that after you leave my sight
希望即使你远离我
it will not be the last time I look upon you."
这也不会是 我最后一次看到你
Finish it With:
结语就写
"With all the love that I possessWilliam."
“献上我所有的爱威廉”
You mean "Ulrich."
你是指“乌瑞克”
"With all the love I possess
献上我所有的爱
I remain yours
我依旧属于你
the knight of your heart."
你芳心中的骑士
My master hoped you might have something to send him in return.
我的主人希望你或许能够 回他几句话
巴黎
Cock a doodle once! I shall not deny him. Twice! I shall not. Thrice!
鸡鸣一次 我不会不承认他！ 鸡鸣两次 我不会！ 三次！
I deny him.
我不承认他
Thrice he denied him!
三次他不承认他
No Adhemar.
阿德玛没参加
Wat.
华特
Tell me,did you see her? Did she read the letter?
告诉我 你见到了她吗？ 她看了信吗？
Yes,and yes.
是的 有的
And?
然后？
She's coming to Paris!
她要来巴黎！
Did she give you anything for me in return? A letter? A token?
她要你带什么回来给我吗？ 一封信？ 一个信物？
Did she give me a token? She did.
她要给我一个信物？ 她有
Uh,I mean,um.
我是说 嗯
Well,what is it? Give it to me.
是什么？ 快给我
Yes!
好耶！
Hell,yes!
太好了！
She-- Because she's-- That means she-- Yeah!
她… 因为她… 那表示她… 太好了！
Cinquante.
五十
That's a nice round number.
那是个不错的整数
Excuse- moi.
借过
They wager that a Frenchman,not Sir Ulrich,will win the tournament.
他们赌法国人 而非乌瑞克爵士会赢得比赛
But the amount is 50 florins.
但赌注是五十个银币
- That's all we got.  - If we had 60,it would be that.
- 那是我们全部的钱  - 就是要赌我们所有的钱
Ulrich against every Frenchman here?
乌瑞克对抗这里每个法国人？
He's won four tournaments in a row. And Adhemar isn't here.
他已经连续赢得四场比赛 而且阿德玛不在这里
I check shields too. John Beaumont's here.
我也查过盾牌了 约翰波蒙在这里
Count Theobald,Philip of Burgundy all French champions.
席德伯爵 勃艮地的菲力浦 都是法国的冠军
Englishmen will not win
英国人无法赢得
this French tournament.
这场法国锦标赛
English legs are unsteady on French soil.
英国人的脚 在法国土地上站不稳
Shut your mouth,all right?!
闭上你的嘴 可以吗？
Come on,Roland. It's a good bet. Win and I can buy my own tavern.
洛伦 赌吧 胜算很大 赢了我就可以买间酒馆
- I could write full- time.  - A forge for me.
- 我就可以专职写作 - 我可以买个炼炉
And because French wine is too much for English bellies.
而且法国酒 对英国人的胃来说也太烈了
Listen,I'm about this fonging close,mate. I swear to God,Quasimodo!
听着 老兄 我就快揍人了 我对上帝发誓 真的！
All I want is to go home,and I've enough for that trip a hundred times.
我只想回家 而且我的钱 够我回家一百次了
And most importantly,because the pope himself is French!
最重要的是 连教宗都是法国人！
The pope may be French,but Jesus is English. You're on.
教宗或许是法国人 但耶稣是英国人 赌了
He won't lose with the princess watching him.
有公主来看他 他不会输的
He's blond! He's pissed!
他金发碧眼！ 他极度恼火！
He'll see you in the lists! Lichtenstein! Lichtenstein!
他会上场的！ 利顿斯坦！ 利顿斯坦！
He's blond! He's tan! He comes from Gelderland!
他金发碧眼！ 他黝黑健壮！ 他来自盖德兰！
He comes from Gelderland!
他来自盖德兰！
Gelderland!
盖德兰！
- You think he will come?  - As sure as the sun will rise.
- 你想他会来吗？  - 就像太阳会升起一样肯定
You favor cathedrals.
你喜欢大教堂
I come for confession.
我是来忏悔的
And the glass.
还有来欣赏玻璃
A riot of color in a dreary,gray world.
一个沉闷灰暗世界里的 缤纷色彩
Don't you think?
你不认为吗？
It's beautiful.
真美
I feel the same about the letter you sent.
你送来的信 也让我有同样的感觉
Speak to me.
跟我说话
Speak those words.
说说那些话
I will win this tournament for you.
我会为你赢得这场锦标赛
Excuse me?
什么？
I'll win this tournament in your name. I'll defeat each knight for you.
我会为你赢得这场锦标赛 我会为你打败每一个骑士
Your beauty will be reflected in the power of my arm and my horse's flanks.
你的美会反映在我手臂的力量 和我马儿的侧腹上
Wow.
哇
Really?
真的？
Really? Its flanks?
真的？ 它的侧腹？
I wish to hear poetry,Ulrich.
乌瑞克 我想听的是诗句
Well,I'm not ready.
我还没准备好
I am. Why must everything for a woman be run on a man's schedule?
我准备好了 为什么女人 事事必须照男人的时间表来？
Well,a man's day is fuller,and
男人要做的事比较多 而且
he has more demands on his time.
他的时间也比较宝贵
- Is that so?  - Yes.
- 是吗？  - 是的
Maybe.
或许吧
No?
不是吗？
I demand poetry
我要听诗句
and when I want it. And I want it now.
我要听 而且现在就要听
Your breasts
你的双峰
they're below your throat.
在你的喉咙下方
Jocelyn,how may I prove my love to you? How?
约瑟琳 我要怎么做才能证明 我对你的爱？ 怎么做？
- Do you ask in earnest?  - Yes.
- 你是认真在问？  - 是的
If you would prove your love
如果你要证明你的爱
- do your worst.  - My worst?
- 就做出你最差的表现  - 最差的表现？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Instead of winning to honor me with your high reputation
不要用你高度的名望 为我赢得大赛
act against your character and do badly.
而是一反常态 表现走样
- Do badly?  - Lose.
- 表现走样？  - 输掉比赛
Losing proves that I'm a loser.
输掉只会证明我是窝囊废
Wrong. Losing is a much keener test of your love.
错 输了更能证明你的爱
Losing would contradict your self- love.
输会跟你的自怜相抵触
It would show obedience to your lover and not yourself!
会显示你对爱人 而非对自己的顺从！
- Really?  - Woman,shh!
- 真的？  - 女人 安静！
Do not "shh" me and spare him! Now be gone! Go!
别叫我安静 而不骂他！ 你走！ 走啊！
What is your answer?
你的答案是什么？
I will not lose.
我不会输的
Then you do not love me.
那么你就不爱我
The Protector of Italian Virginity
意大利贞节的保护者
the Lance that thrilled France
让法国群情激动的骑士
the Harasser of Paraser!
男人中的男人！
He gave them hell at La Rochelle!
在拉罗谢尔打败群敌！
The Enforcer of our Lord God!
上帝旨意的执行者！
The one,the only
独一无二的
Sir Ulrich
乌瑞克
von Lichtenstein!
冯利顿斯坦爵士！
God,I'm good!
天啊 我真行！
His horse's flanks.
他马儿的侧腹
Maybe where he comes from,it means love.
也许在他家乡 那代表了爱
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
- Losing.  - I don't understand.
- 输掉比赛  - 我不懂
I don't understand.too
我也不懂
He loves me.
他爱我
Are you blind?
你瞎了吗？
- Did you see the flag?  - I saw it,okay?
- 你有看到旗子吗？  - 我看到了 可以吗？
I know.
我知道
You're dropping behind for a more dramatic victory.
你故意先落后 再来个戏剧性的胜利
Look,Jocelyn told me to lose to prove my love.
约瑟琳要我输掉比赛 来证明我的爱
- I'd rather you were blind.  - Don't be foolish,Will.
- 我宁可你是瞎掉  - 威廉 你别傻了
- Each woman wants proof,that's all.  - Proof of what?
- 女人不过都想要证明罢了  - 证明什么？
Her legs weren't uncrossed for nothing.
她的腿不是平白无故地分开
- I haven't uncrossed her legs.  - Then why are we doing this?!
- 我没有分开她的腿  - 那我们干嘛这么做？
Because!
就是因为！
Because
因为
I love her.
我爱她
- I'm going to lose everything!  - That's why it's called gambling.
- 我会输光光！  - 所以才叫赌博嘛
Pain! Here's your pain!
痛吧！ 痛死你！
It's very romantic,though.
但是非常罗曼蒂克
Are you a woman or a blacksmith?
你到底是女人还是铁匠？
Sometimes I'm both.
有时候我两者都是
Ooh,that chafes!
好痛啊！ 可恶！
Put him down.
把他放下啦
No knight has distanced himself with victories.
没有骑士会故意输掉
If you win your remaining matches and your opponents take key losses
如果你剩下的几场比赛都赢 而且你的对手都大败特败
you could make the semis,or the finals.
你就可以进入准决赛 或者决赛
- At least the armor's proven itself. - And your love?
- 至少盔甲证明了它的能耐  - 那你的爱呢？
Have you proven that?
你证明你的爱了吗？
Wat,you remember church as a boy. The fear,the passion.
华特 想想小时候对教堂的感觉 那份戒慎恐惧 那份热情
That's what she makes me feel.
那就是我对她的感觉
And for that,I say my rosary to Jocelyn and no one else.
因为如此 我的玫瑰经 只为约瑟琳一个人念
William,that's blasphemous.
威廉 那样说很不敬
Then may I burn in hell.
那就让我在地狱受苦吧
Withdraw.
退出比赛
Lose that way. Take no more punishment.
就这么输了算了 不要再撑下去了
Oh,Roland.
洛伦
My lady sends this message. If you love her- -
我家小姐要我来传话 如果你爱她
I know,I know. I must lose. Isn't she watching?
我知道 我知道 我必须输 她没在看吗？
She says if you love her,you won't lose again.
她说你若爱她 就不会再输了
She says if you love her,you will win this tournament.
她说你若爱她 就会赢得这场大赛
There she is,the embodiment of love. Your Venus.
她在那里 爱的化身 你的维纳斯
And how I hate her.
我真恨她
- I don't understand women.  - Nor do I,but they understand us.
- 我真不懂女人  - 我也不懂 但她们很懂我们
Maybe not you.
也许不包括你
Yes!
好耶！
Women,eh?
女人哪
Forty eight
四十八
forty nine
四十九
and fifty.
五十
Thank you,gentlemen. A pleasure doing business with you.
谢谢各位了 很高兴跟你们做生意
Look us up if you're in London,the world championships,maybe.
到伦敦记得来找我们 也许在世界冠军赛时
Don't look too sad. Here,have a drink on me.
别那么沮丧嘛 拿去 我请你们喝一杯
He's quick,he's funny and makes lots of money,Lichtenstein!
他身手敏捷 他幽默风趣 他还很会赚钱 利顿斯坦！
Guinevere comes to Lancelot.
格温娜维尔走向蓝斯洛
Bed him well,my lady.
小姐 好好服侍他睡
Bed him well.
好好服侍他
We missed you at banquet.
我们在庆祝会上很想你
"We"?
“我们”？
I.
我
Jocelyn.
约瑟琳
Your prize.
你的奖赏
My prize.
我的奖赏
I am not worthy of a prize.
我不配得奖
Then who is?
那么谁有资格？
My maid tells me that sometimes your varlets
我的女仆告诉我 有时候你的属下
call you William.
叫你威廉
Is this so,Sir Ulrich?
是不是 乌瑞克爵士？
Yes.
是的
It is so.
的确如此
Your name makes no matter to me.
你叫什么名字对我不重要
Just so I can call you my own.
只要你是我的
But Jocelyn,I am your own.
但约瑟琳 我的确是你的呀
Damn,girl.
该死
You need a surgeon.
你需要看医生
He's been. He says I will live,though it doesn't feel that way.
他来过了 他说我死不了 虽然不觉的这样
Oh,William. This pain is my doing.
威廉 这疼痛都是我害的
Yes,it is.
的确是
Although
尽管
my father
我父亲
taught me to take the bad
教我要把苦果
with the good.
当良药吃
This good you speak of.
你所说的良药
It will be my doing as well.
也同样会来自于我
How long since any of you have been back? I've only been gone 6 months.
你们上次回来是何时？ 我只离开了六个月
Two years for me.
我两年
Three years.
我三年
Five. Five long years.
五年 漫长的五年
William?
威廉？
Twelve.
十二
Twelve years.
十二年
He's to be an apprentice?
他要去当学徒？
How long for?
多久？
Seven years.
七年
Sir Ector?
艾克特爵士？
I'm the thatcher. I spoke to you outside London Stadium.
我就是在伦敦赛场外 跟您说过话的补屋顶工匠
Oh,yes. I remember.
是的 我记得
Is this the boy?
就是这男孩？
Step forward,son. Let me look at you.
孩子 过来让我看看
Careful with that,Roland!
洛伦 小心点！
Are you afraid of me,boy?
孩子 你怕我吗？
Have you got most of your teeth?
你的牙齿长齐了吗？
Show me your arm. Is it strong?
让我看看你的手臂够壮吗？
Well,he's a half- starved little scarecrow.
他饿得瘦巴巴的
But he has spirit.
但他很有个性
I can show you a great wide world full of adventure
我可以领你见识一个广阔 充满冒险的世界
and marvels you do not yet dream of.
还有你不曾梦想过的 奇人异事
Can you pack my horse and lead it?
可以帮我把东西装上马吗？
Well,come on. Say goodbye to your father.
去吧 跟你父亲道别
He's a real knight,William. Watch and learn all you can.
威廉 他是真正的骑士 尽你所能的观察和学习
It's all I can do for you,son.
我只能为你做到这样了
Now go change your stars and live a better life than I have.
去改变你的命运 过比我好的生活
Roland,show the boy his duties.
洛伦 告诉这孩子该做些什么
- Father? I'm afraid.  - Of what?
- 父亲？ 我怕  - 怕什么？
I won't know the way home.
我会不知道回家的路
Don't be foolish,William. You just follow your feet.
别傻了 威廉 跟随你的脚步就行了
London.
伦敦
世界冠军赛
# Guess who just got back today? #
# 猜猜今天谁回来了？ #
# Them wild-eyed boys that had been away #
# 已经离开的那些狂野的男孩子们 #
# Haven't changed,haven't much to say #
# 没有变化，没有什么太多要说的 #
# But man,I still think them cats are crazy #
# 但是男子汉，我依然觉得爵士迷们很疯狂 #
# They were asking if you were around #
# 他们会问你你是否在周围 #
# How you was,where you could be found #
# 你过的怎么样，你在哪里被发现的 #
# Told them you were living downtown #
# 告诉他们你住在市中心 #
# Driving all the old men crazy #
# 让所有的老男人们都很疯狂 #
# The boys are back in town #
# 男孩子们回到镇上 #
Give us a shout out,London!
为我们欢呼吧 伦敦！
# I said #
# 我说 #
# The boys are back in town #
# 男孩子们回到镇上 #
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
# Spread the word around #
# 把这件事传的沸沸扬扬 #
# Guess who's back in town #
# 猜猜谁回到镇上了 #
# Friday night they'll be dressed to kill #
# 星期五晚上他们打扮的很时尚 #
# Down at Dino's bar and grill #
# 在恐龙酒吧里烧烤 #
# The drink will flow and blood will spill #
# 酒会流出，血会溢出 #
# And if the boys want to fight,you'd better let them #
# 如果男孩子想打架，你最好让他们做 #
# The boys are back in town #
# 男孩子们回到镇上 #
- Adhemar's here. He's entered.  - Must have grown bored with war.
- 阿德玛在这里 他报名了  - 一定是打仗打烦了
No,the Black Prince commanded it. He had to disband his army.
不 是黑王子下的令 他必须解散他的军队
They were reveling,pillaging town after town.
他们每到一个地方 尽会闹事掠夺
Robbing,murdering,ransacking churches.
抢劫、杀人、洗劫教堂
Committing the oldest sins in the newest ways.
用最新的方法 犯下最古老的罪
At last we will face each other again,Sir Ulrich.
我们终将再遭遇 乌瑞克爵士
And at the World Championship.
在这世界冠军赛
And as I promised you before
正如我跟你保证过的
you will look up at me from the flat of your back.
你会躺在地上仰望着我
Let the past die.
忘掉过去吧
You've done well in my absence,on the field and off,I'm told.
据说我不在时 你表现极佳 无论在场内或场外
Winning trophies,horses,women.
赢得奖品、马匹、女人
You put them in that order?
你都是这样排顺序的？
Generally,with a few exceptions.
通常是 但有一些例外
Beautiful,isn't she?
她很美吧？
A real thoroughbred trophy,don't you think?
一项品质精纯的奖品 你不觉得吗？
- You speak of her like a target.  - Isn't she?
- 你说得好像她是箭靶  - 不是吗？
No.
不
She is the arrow.
她是箭
I've begun negotiations with her father.
我已经跟她父亲展开商议了
I'm to make her my bride.
我要她当我的新娘
She'll be saddled
她会被上好鞍
and placed on my mantle.
摆设在我的火炉顶上
Target or arrow,it doesn't matter.
是箭靶或箭并不重要
I will have her.
我将会拥有她
Ulrich! Ulrich! Ulrich!
乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！ 乌瑞克！
- How would you beat him?  - With a sticK,while he slept.
- 你会怎么击倒他？  - 用棍子 趁他熟睡时
But on a horse? With a lance?
但在马上呢？ 用长枪呢？
That man is unbeatable.
那个人所向无敌
Hello there.
你好
- You're Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.  - Yes.
- 你是乌瑞克爵士  - 是的
You're my favorite knight. When we joust,I always say I'm you.
你是我最喜欢的骑士 我们比长枪时 我都说我是你
What are you doing in Cheapside? There's no parade today.
你怎么会来奇普塞？ 今天没有游行啊
Can you keep a secret?
你可以保守秘密吗？
I was born in Cheapside,just around the corner there.
我在奇普塞出生 就在那边的转角
- Truly,Sir Ulrich?  - Truly.
- 真的吗 爵爷？  - 真的
I only live just there.
我就住在那里
How old are you?
你几岁了？
- Nine and one half.  - Nine and one half.
- 九岁半  - 九岁半啊
I wonder if you remember a man,though he may have died long ago.
不知道你是否记得一个人 虽然他可能早就死了
He was as tall as a knight. His name was John Thatcher.
他长得跟骑士一样高大 名字叫约翰柴契尔
- Of course I remember him.  - You do?
- 我当然记得他  - 真的？
Yes. He lives there still.
是啊 他还住在那里
Sometimes we see him sitting at the window,but no one knows why.
有时候我们会看到他坐在窗边 但没有人知道为什么
What do you mean?
什么意思？
He's blind,sir.
他是瞎子 爵爷
Is someone there?
有人来了吗？
If you're here for the net,I'm not done yet. Come tomorrow.
如果你是来拿渔网的 我还没修补好 明天再来吧
Who are you?
你是谁？
A knight.
一个骑士
My nameis Ulrich.
我名叫乌瑞克
Ulrich? I hear that name being chanted from the stadium.
乌瑞克？ 我听过人们 在赛场上高叫这个名字
What business have you here?
有何贵干？
I have word,Master Thatcher.
我有消息 补屋顶师傅
Word of your son.
令公子的消息
Of my William? Well,come in,sir.
我的威廉？ 爵爷 快请进
What word? Does he live?
什么消息？ 他活着吗？
Aye. He lives.
是的 他活着
He is very well.
他很好
He wanted you to know
他希望你知道
that he changed his stars after all.
他终究改变了他的命运
And has he followed his feet?
他跟随了他的脚步吗？
Has he found his way home at last?
他终于找到回家的路了吗？
Yes.
是的
Father.
父亲
Oh,William. Oh,my boy.
威廉 我的孩子
I should like to meet this Wat. And Roland too.
我真想见见这个华特 还有洛伦
You will,Father.
你会见到的
And what of women? Is there a certain one or many?
女人呢？ 你有特定对像 还是很多个？
There is a certain one.
我有一个心仪的对象
I should like to meet her too.
我也想见见她
This leak won't do,Father.
漏水成这样不行
- Not in a thatcher's chamber.  - It's quite fitting for a blind one.
- 尤其在补屋顶工匠家中  - 这对瞎眼人来说不成问题
Well,a thatcher I am.
我是补屋顶的
I'll fix it.
我会帮你修好
Alive. I thought he was dead,which is mad
活着 我以为他死了 我真是疯了
because he was also so strong. Very strong.
因为他仍那么强壮 非常强壮
- Geoff.  - Jocelyn.
- 杰夫  - 约瑟琳
This day just gets better and better.
今天真是愈来愈精采
Somebody die?
有人死了吗？
Sir Ulrich von Lichtenstein.
乌瑞克冯利顿斯坦爵士
Adhemar
阿德玛
followed you last night. To Cheapside.
昨晚跟踪你到奇普塞
He saw your father.
他看到你父亲
Will,they asked me for your patents.
威廉 他们跟我要你的证明书
They're waiting for you in the lists to arrest you.
他们在场上等着逮捕你
A dozen royal guards.
十二个皇家侍卫
- They'll put you in the stocks.  - But I face Adhemar in five minutes.
- 他们会把你抓上示众台  - 但我马上就要跟阿德玛交手
No,you forfeit. They've already marked it down.
不 你丧失了比赛权 他们已经记下了
Saddle the horses. They can arrest your baggage,not you.
把马上鞍 他们可以逮捕你的行李而非你
Halt.
站住
So,what do you think
你有何感想
now that you know what I am?
既然你知道了我是谁？
To know what you are,William,would take a lifetime.
威廉 要知道你是谁 必须花上一辈子的时间
One I am willing to give. But now you must run.
我很愿意这么做 但你现在必须快点跑
Run,and I will run with you.
快跑吧 我会跟你一起跑
Jocelyn,I cannot run.
约瑟琳 我不能跑
I am a knight,and I will put myself to the hazard!
我是个骑士 我要排除万难！
In your heart,not on paper. And paper's what matters to them!
在你心中 不是在文件上 而他们在乎的只有文件！
William,I love you.
威廉 我爱你
I love you. You.
我爱你 只有你
- I won't see you led to the stocks.  - But you'll see me run? No!
- 我不要看你上示众台  - 但要看我逃跑？ 不！
Damn your pride,William.
去你的自尊 威廉
It is only you that will not see you run.
是你不愿意见到自己逃跑
Pride's the one thing they can't take!
自尊是他们夺不走的！
But they can take it from you. They can and they will.
但他们可以践踏你的自尊 他们可以 也会这么做
Oh,they will.
他们绝对会这么做
But love they cannot take.
但他们夺不走爱
And where will we live?
那我们要住在哪里？
In my hovel?
我的破房子吗？
- With the pigs inside in winter?  - Yes,William,with the pigs.
- 在冬天里跟猪共处一室？  - 是的 跟猪共处一室
With the pigs.
跟猪共处一室
The poor can marry for love.
穷人可以为爱结婚
Jocelyn,you speak of what you do not know!
约瑟琳 你不懂！
William,I beg you.
威廉 我求你
Please.
求求你
Run. Do it for love.
跑吧 为了爱
Roland,you would see me run?
洛伦 你要我跑吗？
And you,Geoff?
你呢 杰夫？
I wish it too,with all the pieces of my heart.
我也希望你这么做 衷心这么希望
Wat? You and l? We aren't runners.
华特？ 你跟我？ 我们不轻易逃跑的
Yes.
跑吧
William,today we are.
威廉 今天我们得跑
Run,William.
威廉 跑吧
I will not run!
我不会逃的！
I am a knight.
我是个骑士
Well,boys
各位
all good things must come to an end.
好事终难长久
Let's end them together.
我们就一起做个结束吧
You will remove yourself from this position of honor.
你自愿退出吧
I am here to compete.
我是来参赛的
You are here to be arrested.
你是来被逮捕就范的
All right!
好！
He that strives to touch a star
一心想摘星的人
oft stumbles
往往会失足于
at a simple straw.
一个枝微末节
You have been weighed.
你打也打了
You have been measured.
比也比了
And you have been found wanting.
而且发现你能力不足
It's one loss or anotherWilliam.
世事古难全啊威廉
In what world could you have ever beaten me?
你在哪方面能击败我？
Leave,Roland.
洛伦 你走吧
Let them have me.
随他们高兴吧
God love you,William.
威廉 上帝爱你
So do l.
我也是
Go! Disperse!
走！ 快走开！
Or I will fong you!
不然我要你们好看！
As Jesus Christ the Nazarene and his holy mother
我以拿撒勒的耶稣基督
the Virgin Mary are my witnesses,I will fong you!
和圣母玛丽亚做我的见证 我会要你们好看！
I will rip you! Fist! Pain!
我会揍扁你们！ 痛死你们！
I'll stick my fist and break you! Pain! Lots of pain!
我会打烂你们！ 要你们痛苦！ 非常痛苦！
We're in trouble.
我们麻烦大了
Listen to me.
听我说
What a pair we make,huh?
我们真是哥俩好
Both trying to hide who we are.
都试着隐藏真实身份
Both unable to do so.
却也都失败了
Your men love you.
你的同伴爱你
If I knew nothing else about you,that would be enough.
即使我不了解你 知道这点也就够了
But you also tilt when you should withdraw.
但你在你应该退出的时候 勇敢不屈
That is knightly too.
那也是骑士精神
Release him.
放了他
He may appear to be of humble origins
他或许看来出身低微
but my personal historians have discovered
但我私人的史学家发现
that he descends from an ancient royal line.
他的远祖是皇室成员
This is my word.
这是我说的
And as such,is beyond contestation.
因此 你们不得争辩
Now
现在
if I may repay the kindness you once showed me.
让我回报 你曾经对我展露的情谊
Take a knee.
屈膝跪下吧
By the power vested in me by my father,King Edward
谨以我父王爱德华国王 赋予我的权力
and by all the witnesses here
并在这里所有人的见证下
I dub thee
我封你为
Sir William.
威廉爵士
AriseSir William.
起身吧威廉爵士
Can you joust?
你能上场吗？
There's my tournament to finish.
我还有比赛要完成呢
Now,are you fit to compete,or shall the forfeit stand?
你可以上场比赛 或者还是要弃权？
I'm fit.
我没问题
I shall have your opponent informed. Look for his shield on the lists.
我会找人通知你的对手 去场上找他的盾牌吧
At once.
马上去
Thank you,my lord.
谢谢你 殿下
All hail Prince Edward!
爱德华王子万岁！
My lords,my ladies
各位大人、女士
and all you other people.
和其他人民
I give you the son of Philippe de Vitry,son of Gilles.
请欢迎菲利浦德维崔之子 吉列之孙
- Are you sure?  - Yes.
- 你确定吗？  - 确定
It's nothing but spun sugar and boot black.
这不过是漆了黑漆的糖衣
It's a small target
目标虽然小
but aim for his heart.
瞄准他的心脏
doer of daring deeds
功勋彪炳
conqueror of countless kingdoms,Count
所向披靡的伯爵
Adhemar!
阿德玛！
Oh,God. I'll get the surgeon.
天啊 我去找医生
Roland!
洛伦！
You're the surgeon.
你就是医生
Come on.
快点
He tipped it.
他装了尖头
Kate,get me back to one.
凯蒂 快领我回起点
Otherwise we forfeit.
否则我们就得弃权
Dirty son of a bitch!
那个黑心的浑蛋！
Kate,I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
凯蒂 我没办法呼吸
As I said,thatcher.
正如我说的 补屋顶工匠
In what world could you have ever beaten me?
你在哪方面能击败我？
Such a place does not exist.
那方面是不存在的
She's here.
她来了
With your father.
和你的父亲一起来了
Change your stars.
改变命运
Let's dance,you and l.
你我好好比一场吧
It's two lances to none.
目前是二比零
You must unhorse him or kill him. It's the only way to win.
你得让他落马或杀了他 才能获胜
- You need more padding.  - No,leave it off.
- 你需要多加些衬垫  - 不了 我不穿了
I can't breathe with it on.
穿着我会无法呼吸
Lance.
长枪给我
I can barely grip it.
我抓都抓不稳
Damn.
可恶
Lash it to my arm.
把枪绑在我手臂上
Wat
华特
Iash it to me arm.
把枪绑在我手臂上
Do it.
照他说的做
Good people!
各位！
I missed my introduction!
我忘了说介绍词！
But please
但请你们
please,I pray you.
请你们 请求你们
Hear it now.
现在好好倾听
For I would lay rest
因为我接下来
the grace in my tongue
放下花言巧语
and speak plain.
只说简单的
Days like these
像今天这种罕见的机会
are far too rare to cheapen with heavy- handed words.
不该让拙劣的言词 贬损了它的价值
And so,I'm afraid,without any ado whatsoever
因此 我想 我就不再无事自扰
Excuse me,my lord.
大人 抱歉
Here he is! One of your own!
他就在那里！ 你们的同胞！
Born a stone's throw from this very stadium
在这个场上诞生的璞石
and here before you now.
现在就在你们的面前
The son of John Thatcher
约翰柴契尔之子
Sir William Thatcher!
威廉柴契尔爵士！
That's your name.
那是你的名字
Sir William Thatcher.
威廉柴契尔爵士
Your father heard that.
你父亲听到了
Godspeed,William.
威廉 祝你成功
William!
威廉！
You have been weighed.
你打也打了
You've been measured.
比也比了
And you absolutely
而且绝对的
have been found wanting.
能力不足
Welcome to the new world.
欢迎来到新世界
God save you,if it is right that he should do so.
愿上帝保全你 如果他这么做是对的
William!
威廉！
Yes!
太好了！
He's won! He's won!
他赢了！ 他赢了！
You beat him,Will!
威廉 你打败了他！
Oh,William.
威廉
I'm going to write this story.
我要写下这个故事
About the prince and the knights?
王子和骑士的故事？
No,all of it. All human activity lies within the artist's scope.
不 全部 一个艺术家要写尽人事
Maybe not yours.
你的就免了
# She was a fast machine,#
# 她其实就是一台高速运转的机器 #
# She kept her motor clean,#
# 只不过让自己的发动机永葆清洁 #
# She was the best damn woman that I ever seen,#
# 她也许是我见过最好的女人 #
# She had sightless eyes,#
# 因为她有一双不明晰的眼睛  #
# Telling me no lies,#
# 而且她从不撒谎 #
# Knocking me out with those American thighs,#
# 用那美国式的胴体诱惑把我制服 #
# Taking more than her share,#
# 我试图索取更多 #
# Had me fighting for air,#
# 结果我却不堪重负 #
# She told me to come,but I was already there,#
# 她说来吧 事实上我已经在那了 #
# Cause the walls started shaking,#
# 然后墙就开始抖动 #
# The earth was quaking,#
# 大地也在晃动 #
# My mind was aching,#
# 我的思想已经极度疼痛 #
# And we were making it and you #
# 你知道我们在干什么 因为你 #
# Shook me all night long,#
# 整晚的折磨我 #
# All night long #
# I've paid my dues #
# 我已付出了代价 #
# Time after time #
# 一次又一次 #
# I've done my sentence #
# 我服了刑 #
# But committed no crime #
# 但没有犯罪 #
# And bad mistakes #
# 我犯过了一些 #
# I've made a few #
# 严重的错误 #
# I've had my share of sand,kicked in my face #
# 我自作自受 #
# But I've come through #
# 但我都熬过来了 #
# And I need to go on and on and on and on #
# 我要继续 #
# We are the champions,my friends #
# 我们是冠军 我的朋友们 #
# And we'll keep on fighting till the end #
# 我们会一直战斗到最后 #
# We are the champions #
# 我们是冠军 #
# No time for losers #
# 这世界不属于失败者 #
# 'Cause we are the champions of the world #
# 因为我们是世界冠军 #
# I've taken my bows #
# 我鞠躬谢幕 #
# And my curtain calls #
# 将落下帷幕 #
# You've bought me fame and fortune #
# 你们给我带来名誉和财富 #
# And everything that goes with it #
# 和随之而来的一切 #
# I thank you all #
# 我感谢你们 #
# But it's been no bed of roses there #
# 但没有任何游乐 #
# No pleasure cruise #
# 也不是欢乐的海洋 #
# I consider it a challenge before the whole human race #
# 我认为这是一个摆在全人类面前的挑战 #
# And I ain't gonna lose #
# 而我绝不会输 #
# And I need to go on and on and on and on #
# 我要继续 #
# We are the champions,my friends #
# 我们是冠军 我的朋友们 #
# And we'll keep on fighting till the end #
# 我们会一直战斗到最后 #
# We are the champions #
# 我们是冠军 #
# No time for losers #
# 这世界不属于失败者 #
# 'Cause we are the champions #
# 因为我们是世界冠军 #
# We are the champions #
# 我们是冠军 #
# No time for losers #
# 这世界不属于失败者 #
# 'Cause we are the champions #
# 因为我们是冠军 #
Your round.
你输了